[
    {
        "_id" : "1",
        "question" : "\u201CShe was weird. She always started her counting from 4.<br> Once her husband asked which day it is, she said Thursday while it was Sunday.<br> One day, after purchasing 4 apples she gave money to the seller for 8 apples. <br>She left a note which reads \"WLIVPSGO\"\r\n, What did she mean?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "sherlock",
        "hint" : "4 is the new one"
    },
    {
        "_id" : "2",
        "question" : "It was another mysterious case of sudden disappearance of Mr. Schlansky.<br> A laptop is found in his office and needs to be accessed in order to get a clue about his whereabouts but it was password protected with a hint as follows:\r\n\r\n<br><b>Take the 4th pineapple and eat them with the 4th toast.</b><br> <b>If you don\u2019t guess the password within the 3rd duck, then eat the 1st apricot kept to the side of 1st paper guarded by the 4th tiger.</b><br>\r\n\r\nCan you help find the password?\r\n\r\n",
        "answer" : "escape",
        "hint" : " A wise man said, “Math is fun”, who knew although being fun, it can take a person to the right PLACE."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "3",
        "question" : "\u201CJorge Manley, a famous businessman was murdered. <br>Yet no murderer was found. But the cops got witnesses. <br>There were 5 other people in Jorge\u2019s house. <br>The Chef(Jack) said he was preparing breakfast. <br>The Gardener(Jacob) said he was gardening. <br>The Maid(Andrea) was outside cleaning the window as there was fog all over. <br>The Wife(Lisbon) said she was watching TV. <br>And then the grandfather(George) said he was in his wheelchair.<br> Who murdered Jorge Manley<b> (Name)</b>?\u201D\r\n\r\n\r\n\r\n",
        "answer" : "Andrea",
        "hint" : "A murderer always tries to make CLEAR that there is no evidence left behind."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "4",
        "question" : "\u201CAndrea was found dead in her hotel room. <br>\r\n\r\nIn the room, all the fingerprints had been eliminated with ammonia. <br>The label of the ammonia bottle used to clear the evidence was found which linked to the pharmaceutical company that Carl owned.<br> \r\n\r\nThere was a handwritten Note which said, \"She deserved this.\" in a neat handwriting.<br> \r\nA piece of torn cloth was found which turned out to be Carl's.<br> This was an indication that there had been a struggle, however, there was no other evidence to support this cause. <br>\r\n\r\nFurther investigation revealed that Carl suffered feats of aggression. <br>\r\n\r\nAndrea was a troubled woman and had attempted suicide in the past. <br>Carl used to lash out by beating her.<br> The police concluded that this was a case of suicide made to look like murder.<br>\r\nWhat piece of evidence gave it away?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "note",
        "hint" : "The clue is in Carl’s condition"
    },
    {
        "_id" : "5",
        "question" : "\u201CCarl\u2019s 13 yrs old daughter Olivia, disappeared from the bedroom. In the bathroom, there was a glass in front of the mirror and a bathtub filled with water below it .<br>They wrote on the glass that this may help us to reach the daughter-  <br>\u201Ccall me at u3^373  - S.H.\u201D. <br>What did they mean?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "eleven",
        "hint" : "\u201CTo find Olivia one doesn\u2019t need help .\r\n      All must do is look to REFLECT upon what's important.\u201D\r\n"
    },
    {
        "_id" : "6",
        "question" : "Two archaeologists standing on the Greenwich meridian wanted to meet their undercover friend for help. They wanted to meet him but he couldn\u2019t share his address directly. So he made a puzzle for them to solve which would lead to the country he is in.\r\n\r\nHe sent both of them to a warehouse where they found the address to two different warehouses. One was towards the north and the other was towards the east.\r\nBoth of them decided to split and go to those warehouses.<br>\r\nOne who went to the north found a letter with a mathematical question in it\r\n\r\nQuestion:\r\n\r\nThe triangle ABC  has sides a=5, b=18.76, and c=15.398 find angle C.<br>\r\n\r\nOther who went to the east found the same question but had to find the angle A <br>\r\n\r\nAfter solving the problem, both of them met and thought about the clues that were given and were successful to find the country hidden in it.\r\n\r\n<br>Find the country and meet Olivia\r\n-With love S.H.\r\n",
        "answer" : "Italy",
        "hint" : "Not only the degrees of the angle but also the direction is required to find the location."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "7",
        "question" : "\u201CHello Sherlock and John. Actually, I don\u2019t feel like giving the daughter right away. <br>Solve this puzzle...\r\n\u2018A chemistry teacher was murdered soon after his last lecture, Wednesday evening.\r\nA note was found which read \u2192  044.083.010.008.<br>\r\nBreak the code and find the names of two murderers\u2019 \u201D\r\n<br><b>Note : Answer Format-(first_murderer space second_murderer) </b>",
        "answer" : "RuBi NeO",
        "hint" : "It is a table without legs."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "8",
        "question" : "\u201CI have 2 friends, Scarlett and Erin.<br> Scarlett lies on Mondays, Tuesdays, Wednesdays and Fridays. <br>Whereas Erin lies on Mondays, Tuesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, Sundays.<br>\r\nToday they give the following statements.<br>\r\nScarlett- I lie on Saturdays.\r\nErin- I will lie tomorrow.\r\nScarlett- I'll lie on Sundays as well.\r\nErin:- I will lie the day after tomorrow.\r\n\r\n<br>Which day is today?\u201D \r\n",
        "answer" : "wednesday",
        "hint" : "Find an odd one out."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "9",
        "question" : "\u201CA group of 5 friends went on an adventure. They decided to climb a mountain.It was a winter evening, they started their journey in extreme cold.<br> Two days later, when they were starting their climb for the day, they found Scarlett's body and she was poisoned.<br> On investigating, Joe told that he was packing the bag. <br>Hamid said he was the last to wake up. <br>Erin told that she was cooking food for all and Winston said that he was mapping their route for the journey.<br>\r\nWho is most likely to be the killer?\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "Erin",
        "hint" : "Winston said that the last time he saw Scarlett was before breakfast."
    },
    {
        "_id" : "10",
        "question" : "\u201CFour robbers Leo, Tommy, Harrison & Arlo planned to rob a bank.<br> They entered the bank on a busy morning and sealed all entrances. One hostage was found dead. During the investigation Leo said he was breaking into the locker room.<br> Arlo said he was looting all the cash from the cash desk. Harrison said he was guarding the entrances. Tommy said he was disabling the security cameras and alarms. <br>Who killed the hostage?\u201D",
        "answer" : "harrison",
        "hint" : "Can someone do something that has already been done?"
    },
    {
        "_id" : "11",
        "question" : "\u201CHello Shelly boy! Welcome to the final round. \r\nI have to admit, I feel like this has gone on for too long now and you definitely deserve a rest.<br> But I can\u2019t help but imagine you twitching so hard to get your hands on me given all the pain I have caused you. Hah! I LOVE IT! Don\u2019t worry, Sherlock, even I am excited to meet you after all this, the look on your face will be worth more than gold!<br> Trust me, it will happen and it will be priceless!\r\nBut for that you have to pull through one LAST round. Be my good boy and finish it! \r\n\r\nThere\u2019s a donkey murdered with a note on its tail. \r\nNote said \u201CYou would need an eight legged table to solve that.\r\n<br>Take this number you may need it, 150 165 142 145 162 164.\u201D\r\n<br>The only way to get to the murderer is to solve the mystery note.\u201D\r\n",
        "answer" : "hubert",
        "hint" : "Donkey is  with the key"
    }
]
